VASANTHAAN **NATARAJAN MARAN**

Toronto, Canada M1K 2M1 | 647-581-2692 | vasanththarun5@gmail.com

Summary

Performance-oriented interface designer with excellent understanding of technologies, accessibility requirements and performance capabilities. Dedicated to optimizing human-computer interactions for diverse applications. Strong conceptualization ability, attention to detail, and creative eye, able to solve complex business challenges, while keeping in mind needs of the end user or internal business partners.

Soft Skills

- Leadership
- Problem Solving
- · Creative Thinking
- Collaboration
- Active Listening

- Adaptation
- Teamwork
- Communication
- Empathy
- Flexibility

Software Skills

• Adobe Master Suite, Figma, Sketch, Maya, VS code, Unity, InVision, Mudbox

Hard Skills

• Research, Information Architecture, Wireframing, Prototyping, Visual Communication, Usability Testing, Video & Audio editing, Motion Graphics, Animation, HTML/CSS/JAVA

Experience

Interactive Media Designer Dankos Media Group

11/2022 to Current Toronto, ON

- Developed, implemented and strengthened social media-based marketing campaigns, web assets and product promotions.
- Developed, designed, laid out and produced variety of technical illustrations for brochures, banners and signs.
- Created graphics and animations using traditional and cutting-edge techniques.
- Worked with companies such as 123 tequila, sparks financial group, The truffle kings and more to help develop their brand identity.

Social Media Volunteer

Landed for Success

08/2022 to Current Toronto, ON

- Crafted visual designs and brand messaging elements for consistency across digital advertising and marketing platforms.
- Updated and monitored content on Facebook, LinkedIn and Instagram.
- Utilized editing and photography tools to enhance storytelling.
- Partnered with content management and video associates to create customer success stories for promotion on social media networks.

Graphic Designer

Tamil Entertainment Television, Canada

01/2020 to 11/2020

Toronto, ON

Enhanced filmed segments with programmed computerized graphic effects.

- Edited recorded segments to insert music, dialogue and sound effects.
- Operated Adobe Photoshop and After Effects software to edit footage.
- Solitarily created title cards, logo animation, Motion package for TV programs.
- Developed, designed, laid out and produced variety of technical illustrations for brochures, banners and signs.

UI/UX Designer 11/2018 to 08/2019
Origin Chennai, Tamilnadu

- Generated UX concepts such as tasks analysis, storyboards and use cases to accelerate user flow.
- Worked with product designers and product managers to design user interactions in applications.
- Created User-friendly design for apps by following WCAG guidelines.
- Reviewed solutions to verify alignment with customer objectives, organization guidelines and benchmarks and industry best practices.
- Developed custom web application interfaces with HTML and CSS to meet client requirements.
- Crafted digital branding based on UI system layout, asset identification and project requirements.

Education and Training

Post Graduate Diploma: Interactive Media Design

Seneca College of Applied Arts And Technology

Advanced Diploma: Graphic Designing And Interactive Media

Toronto Film School

Bachelor of Science: Visual Communication

SRM Arts And Science College

08/2022

North York, ON

12/2020

Toronto, ON

0.4/0.04.0

04/2019

Chennai, India

Websites

https://vash07.github.io/My-website/

Certifications

Certified Graphic designer, National Skill Development Corporation (NSDC) - 2019